academicearth.org 2019-01-12

# Privacy Policy | Academic Earth

Terms of Use and Privacy Policy for Use of AcademicEarth.org® (Effective January 14, 2016)

Thank you for your interest in AcademicEarth.org, and for utilizing our content and resources. We will go over our terms of use and privacy policy on this page, explaining the conditions in which you may use our website, as well as what data AcademicEarth.org collects and how that data is used. 

Your interaction with AcademicEarth.org indicates your agreement to the following Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. It also indicates your acknowledgement and agreement that the information gathered on this website may be shared with schools, affiliated companies, and third parties so that they may provide you with the materials you have requested, including degree details and other education-related products and services. In addition, you acknowledge and agree that AcademicEarth.org retains the right to release any collected information as necessary to businesses providing an administrative service, such as email delivery. This includes the release of personally identifiable information.

When you submit personal information to AcademicEarth.org, you are granting us and our affiliated entities (including schools, third-party marketing partners, and vendors) permission to contact you for a certain period of time. This includes contact through telephone, text messages, email, and/or postal mail for the purpose of providing information and marketing for education-related products and services. In addition, you give us and our affiliated entities permission to bypass any rights granted to you by the Do Not Call list or other applicable law because by submitting information on this website, you omit yourself from the Do Not Call requirements established by state and federal governments.

We also retain the right to release your personal information when it is a legal requirement. This includes when abiding to a subpoena or other legal procedure, when doing so is necessary to preserve our rights, to explore alleged fraud, to protect the safety of you and/or others, and/or in the event that AcademicEarth.org is merging, acquisitioning, or selling some or all of its assets to a third party.

## Data Collection

AcademicEarth.org collects two types of data: submitted and automatic information. 

Submitted information is voluntarily provided by the user, and may include:

  * Name
  * Phone number
  * Address
  * Email
  * Any other information required to match you to a product or service

This is typically submitted through a web-based form, and is collected and stored by AcademicEarth.org. It is shared with schools and other third parties so that we may provide you with information about schools, programs, and other education-related services. By submitting this information, you authorize AcademicEarth.org, as well as our affiliated schools and partners, to contact you in accordance with all applicable laws. If you receive any email communications from us, a school, or third party, you can unsubscribe through a link in the email, which will remove you from the mailing list of that sender.

Automatic information is data collected and stored whenever visitors interact with AcademicEarth.org, and includes (but is not limited to):

  * Browser version
  * Operating system version
  * IP address

This anonymous information is used to help us to improve the website and create a more tailored user experience. “Cookies” are utilized to collect this automatic data, which is utilized for analytics, site optimization, and for advertising and marketing purposes. 

Cookies are small pieces of data sent from a website and stored in the user’s web browser. These are used for technical purposes, such as web analytics. AcademicEarth.org’s web analytics are primarily run using Google Analytics, a tool provided by Google, Inc. These advertising cookies, which are sometimes referred to as third-party cookies because they track navigation and publish ads on behalf of third parties, do not contain personally identifiable information. They do, however, enable advertisers to make ads more relevant to the user’s interests. For more information about Google Analytics, check [Google’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html).

By using this website, you acknowledge that AcademicEarth.org uses cookies and consent to our use of cookies. 

Here are some examples of how we may use cookies, including uses through services and partnerships with vendors and third-party service providers:

  * Looking at demographic and other anonymous data for web optimization and other analysis
  * “Lead auditing” to ensure the accuracy, relevance, and validity of submitted information
  * Marketing and conversion tracking cookies, used for targeting and optimizing digital ad serving to improve relevance, user experience, and advertising effectiveness

You can remove cookies through your browser settings, but you may need to do this per usage. You can also generally opt out of receiving personalized ads from third-party advertisers and ad networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) or that follow the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. To do so, visit the opt-out pages on the NAI website and DAA websites.

## Terms of Use and Privacy Policy Changes Notification

We could possibly revise our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy in the future if we change our practices. To remain current and informed on our policies, we recommend that you revisit this page periodically.

If you have any questions or concerns about this Terms of Use and Privacy Policy, please use our contact form.
